EMEHELU RAPHAEL ONWURA

Address: Prince and Princess Estate, Duboyi District, FCT Abuja.

Phone: +234(0) 8164493471

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/raphael-emehelu-20724b13a/

GitHub: https://github.com/rafaelpascal

Email: rafaelpascal234@gmail.com, ozor.rafael@gmail.com

CAREER SUMMARY

A skilled software developer with over 3 years of experience, I am committed to delivering cost-effective and timely results while working within project specifications. With a strong passion for technology and a keen interest in learning, I am always looking for ways to grow and advance my skills.

SKILLS

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Tech-savvy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER APPMART INTEGRATED LIMITED

January 2022 – present, FCT, ABUJA

Subeb Pay Slip Platform Backend

- Using Node Js I was able to develop API to onboard staff into a platform, accept their Verification Number from their Pay slip and store their details in Mongo DB with a detailed Authentication and Authorization approach made sure that access to the platform is very secured.
- I Was able to create endpoint that will receive pay slips records from an external API and store in my
 Database Then pull the record from my Database when user request for their pay slip send to their email or
 generate PDF file which can be download to devices.

New Hall School website, Admin UI and Backend

- Using Node Js I was able to develop a backend service for a school Website creating Endpoints that will
 enable an Admin to Create another admin, upload the school calendar in excel format which will be
 displayed in the school website for viewers and also a pdf that can be downloaded.
- Using React Js I was able to develop the school website and the admin UI from which the admin can perform tasks.

Email and SMS Sender

• Using Node Js I was able to develop and endpoint for the Company that will accept an Excel file pick out their Individual Email and/or Phone and send message to them.

Company Staff Report App

• Built a frontend where users can come to create account and using a Rich Text Editor collect the information of what they did for the week.

 Built a Backend that Accepts users details during sign up and Sign in with full authentication and authorization process, stores their information in Mongo DB database, also can accept and persist the work they did for the week.

Payment option

• Built a Backend where my API makes a call to an external API which then Generates account Detail for a user to make payment with.

VAS Integration

• Using Node JS Mongo DB, I was able to integrate to Xpress payment Services, integrated to their Airtime, Data, Education, Electricity Etc so that the company client can buy airtime, data through them.

Nicetel Admin UI and Backend

- Using React Js, Tailwind CSS I was able to develop an admin UI for admin.nicetel.com.ng, and
- Using Node Js I developed a well-structured, detailed backend service that uses MySQL DB to persist User's Data.

Agrify Mobile App/AdminUI/ Backend

- Using React Native, Tailwind CSS, Typescript I was able to develop a mobile App,
- Using Node JS, MySQL I Was able to develop the backend Service that is connected to the Agrify mobile app and Admin UI.
- Currently Working on the admin UI of Agrify Admin UI.

Skolasuite (School portal)

• Part of the Development Team that developed a School Portal, for the management of a school.

Staff Verification Portal (One ID)

- Part of the Development Team that Developed a Staff Verification Portal for an external Organization.
- Built an Endpoint for the communication of email and SMS messages to multiple users in at once.

DATA Upload

• Developed a Backend project that accept an excel file and store in MySQL Database.

Amazon Store Clone (Practical Project)

• Using React Js I was able to develop an amazon store for practical purposes.

Personal Portfolio (Practical Project)

• Using React JS, Tailwind CSS I was able to develop some personal portfolio for practical purposes.

SALES EXECUTIVE

APPMART INTEGRATED LIMITED

September 2019 – December 2021, Awka, Anambra State.

- Managed and Trained 30+ Anambra State Internal Revenue Staffs on the use of many revenue App developed by the Appmart Integrated Limited.
- Part of the team that Managed and Trained 30+ Imo State Internal Revenue Staffs on the use of many revenue App developed by the Appmart Integrated Limited.
- Ran multiple stress Test on developed Application.

- Using Excel Spreadsheet to manage and organize payments made through the company system.
- Performed multiple Zoom Training for the company.

ASSISTANT MANAGER.

Aloy Peace Computer Center

January 2013 – January 2014, Anambra State.

- Managing the Company financial records.
- Attending to Customer's.

EDUCATION

• FEDERAL POLYTECHNIC OKO.

HND. Computer Science June 2016 | Anambra State GPA 3.41

• CONVENANT POLYTECHNIC.

ND. Computer Science September 2014 | Abia State, Aba GPA 3.26

DEVAMPLIFY

Web Development 2020

CODEDAMN

JavaScript Basics Certificate of Completion March 2022

CODEDAMN

Node Js Certificate of Completion May 2022

PIRPLE

JavaScript: ES6 Certificate of Completion May 2022

PIRPLE

Node Js Master Class Certificate of Completion May 2022

NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORP

2018 | Anambra State

• DIGITAL EXPERIENCE COMMUNICATIONS.

Desktop Publishing 2014 | Anambra State Distinction

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/folders/1QmjN7zr3_ZWZIacvLBkiTnbavxbrI7ZY

REFEREE

• Available on request.